National Visionary Leadership Project Interviews and Conference Collection AFC 2004/007
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series III: Interviews
  - Fred Gray oral history interview conducted by Celia Carey Meyer, 2008-06-27, AFC 2004/007: 302
    - Moving Images, 4 videocassettes of 4 (DVCam) (256 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 302.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 302.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 302.MV.003; AFC 2004/007: 302.MV.004
  - Nebraska Mays oral history interview conducted by Shanna Lewis, 2002-10-24, AFC 2004/007: 303
    Nebraska Mays was a professor of education and administrator at Fisk University and Tennessee State University.
    Nebraska Mays was interviewed on October 24, 2002 for the National Visionary Leadership Project, by Shanna Lewis, a National Visionary Heritage Fellow, Fisk University, in Nashville, Tennessee.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655242
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 303.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 303.MV.002
  - Irma Carson oral history interview conducted by Cori Tucker, 2007-10-21, AFC 2004/007: 304
    Irma Carson was a city council member in Bakersfield, California.
    Irma Carson was interviewed on October 21, 2007 for the National Visionary Leadership Project, by Cori Tucker, a National Visionary Heritage Fellow, UCLA, in Los Angeles, California.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655236
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (128 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 304.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 304.MV.002
  - H. Carl McCall oral history interview conducted by Camille O. Cosby, 2007-01-22, AFC 2004/007: 305
    H. Carl McCall was a New York State Senator, State Comptroller and civic leader.
    The interview includes Carl McCall's memories of growing up in Boston, Massachusetts, attending Dartmouth College and serving in the army. He recalls attending the University of Edinburgh for his degree in theology, his position as chairman of the Council Against Poverty and his election to the New York State Senate. He discusses serving on the New York City Department of Education, his election as New York State Comptroller and his career at Citibank.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655233
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (79 pages) (Box-folder 24/322)
    - Graphic Images, 4 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/528)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (DVCam) (128 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 305.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 305.MV.002
Index of Interviewees
Adams, Clara AFC 2004/007: 123
Adams, Joe, 1922- AFC 2004/007: 001
Alexander, Clifford L., 1933- AFC 2004/007: 002
Alexander, John Melvin AFC 2004/007: 229
Allen, Lucy, 1932- AFC 2004/007: 230
Allen, Vivian Ayers AFC 2004/007: 245
Anderson, Sarah Lee, 1926- AFC 2004/007: 124
Angelou, Maya AFC 2004/007: 003
Archer, Lee, 1919-2010 AFC 2004/007: 004
Banks, Ernie, 1931- AFC 2004/007: 005
Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934- AFC 2004/007: 125
Barrow, Willie T. (Willie Taplin), 1924- AFC 2004/007: 006
Barthé, Earl, 1922-2010 AFC 2004/007: 246
Belisle, Rudolph, 1932- AFC 2004/007: 126
Bell, Derrick A. AFC 2004/007: 007
Bendolph, Mary Lee, 1935- AFC 2004/007: 265 AFC 2004/007: 266
Bennett, Lerone, 1928- AFC 2004/007: 008
Betts, Keter AFC 2004/007: 127
Birch, Adolpho A., 1932- AFC 2004/007: 128
Bird, Van S., 1924- AFC 2004/007: 129
Blackwell, David, 1919-2010 AFC 2004/007: 009
Bodenhamer, Arnett, 1933- AFC 2004/007: 166
Booker, Kinney Ivis AFC 2004/007: 229
Booker, Simeon, 1918- AFC 2004/007: 247
Bowman, Lillie, 1924- AFC 2004/007: 130
Boyles, Pecolia, 1926- AFC 2004/007: 131
Bradley, J. Robert (John Robert), 1920-2007 AFC 2004/007: 132
Brantley, William, E., 1934- AFC 2004/007: 133
Branton, Leo, Jr., 1922- AFC 2004/007: 248
Bromery, Randolph W. (Randolph Wilson), 1926- AFC 2004/007: 010
Brooke, Edward William, 1919- AFC 2004/007: 011
Brooks, Jerome A. AFC 2004/007: 134
Brown, Calvin, 1936- AFC 2004/007: 012
Brown, Chuck, 1936-2012 AFC 2004/007: 239
Brown, Eleanor DeLoache AFC 2004/007: 135
Brown, Oscar AFC 2004/007: 013
Brown, Roscoe Conkling, 1922- AFC 2004/007: 014
Brown, Wesley A., 1927-2012 AFC 2004/007: 233
Brown, Willie L. AFC 2004/007: 015
Browne, Roscoe Lee AFC 2004/007: 016
Bryant, Curtis C., 1917-2007 AFC 2004/007: 017
Burke, Yvonne Brathwaite AFC 2004/007: 018
Burnett, Arthur L., 1935- AFC 2004/007: 136
Burnett, Calvin W., 1932- AFC 2004/007: 137
Burns, Joe Ira AFC 2004/007: 229
Burroughs, Margaret Taylor, 1915-2010 AFC 2004/007: 138
Butcher, Vada E. AFC 2004/007: 139
Caldwell, Earl AFC 2004/007: 140
Cameron, James, 1914-2006 AFC 2004/007: 019
Camphor, James, 1927- AFC 2004/007: 141
Carreathers, Ernestine, 1925- AFC 2004/007: 142
Carroll, Diahann AFC 2004/007: 235
Carson, Irma AFC 2004/007: 304
Carson, Julia AFC 2004/007: 143
Carter, Robert L., 1917-2012 AFC 2004/007: 020
Catlett, Elizabeth, 1915-2012 AFC 2004/007: 021
Chambers, Julius L. (Julius LeVonne), 1936- AFC 2004/007: 236
Charles, Ray, 1930-2004 AFC 2004/007: 022
Chase, Leah AFC 2004/007: 023
Chineworth, Mary Alice AFC 2004/007: 024
Chisholm, Shirley, 1924-2005 AFC 2004/007: 025
Christian, Mary T. AFC 2004/007: 249
Churchwell, Robert, 1917-2009 AFC 2004/007: 144
Clark, Otis G. AFC 2004/007: 229
Clarke, Mildred I., 1934- AFC 2004/007: 145
Clifford, Margaret Washington, 1921-2009 AFC 2004/007: 146
Coachman, Alice AFC 2004/007: 026
Cobb, Moses, 1930- AFC 2004/007: 250
Coffey, Vernon, 1928- AFC 2004/007: 251
Cole, Maria, 1922-2012 AFC 2004/007: 252
Coleman, Calvin Bedell, 1921- AFC 2004/007: 253
Coleman, William T. (William Thaddeus), 1920- AFC 2004/007: 027
Coles, Marion AFC 2004/007: 291 AFC 2004/007: 291a
Collier, Eugenia W. AFC 2004/007: 148
Collins, Cardiss, 1931- AFC 2004/007: 028
Collins, Marva AFC 2004/007: 237
Comer, James P. AFC 2004/007: 238
Conyers, John, 1929- AFC 2004/007: 241
Crittenden, Flora, 1924- AFC 2004/007: 150
Cunningham, Evelyn, 1916-2010 AFC 2004/007: 029
Daughtry, Herbert, 1931- AFC 2004/007: 254
Davis, Ossie AFC 2004/007: 030
Davis, Wendell C., 1931-2009 AFC 2004/007: 151
De Lavallade, Carmen, 1931- AFC 2004/007: 031
Dee, Ruby AFC 2004/007: 030
Deas, Gerald W., 1931- AFC 2004/007: 152
Dellums, Ronald V., 1935- AFC 2004/007: 231
DeVore-Mitchell, Ophelia, 1922- AFC 2004/007: 033
Dews, Maggie, 1914- AFC 2004/007: 255
Dial, Thornton AFC 2004/007: 256
Dickens, Georgia, 1920- AFC 2004/007: 153
Dinkins, David N. AFC 2004/007: 034
Dixon, Joyce M., 1936- AFC 2004/007: 257
Dobson, Betty Jean, 1930- AFC 2004/007: 154
Dorn, Roosevelt F., 1935- AFC 2004/007: 258
Douglas, Shirley, 1933- AFC 2004/007: 155
Driskell, David C. AFC 2004/007: 035
Du Bois, David Graham AFC 2004/007: 036
Dugas, Julian, 1918- AFC 2004/007: 259
Duncantell, Ovide, 1936- AFC 2004/007: 260
Dunham, Katherine AFC 2004/007: 037
Edmonds, Elizabeth Arthur, 1924- AFC 2004/007: 156
Elders, M. Joycelyn AFC 2004/007: 038
Ellis, Elaine, 1917- AFC 2004/007: 292 AFC 2004/007: 293
Ellis, Vivian Ann, 1929- AFC 2004/007: 157
Ennis, Ethel, 1932- AFC 2004/007: 039
Evans, Clay, Rev. AFC 2004/007: 159
Evers-Williams, Myrlie AFC 2004/007: 040
Farrakhan, Louis AFC 2004/007: 261
Faulcon, Clarence, 1928- AFC 2004/007: 262
Faulcon, Jacqueline B. AFC 2004/007: 263
Fauntroy, Walter E. AFC 2004/007: 041 AFC 2004/007: 041b
Fiest, Bernice, 1923- AFC 2004/007: 160
Forman, James, 1928-2005 AFC 2004/007: 042
Foster, Henry W., 1933- AFC 2004/007: 161
Francis, Norman C., 1931- AFC 2004/007: 162
Franklin, Anna B., 1932- AFC 2004/007: 264
Franklin, Frederick C., 1929- AFC 2004/007: 264
Franklin, John Hope, 1915-2009 AFC 2004/007: 042a
Frederick, Lafayette, 1923- AFC 2004/007: 163
Freeman, Frankie Muse, 1916- AFC 2004/007: 044
Gilliam, Sam, 1933- AFC 2004/007: 269
Gooding, Jesse O., 1926- AFC 2004/007: 164
Goodwin, James O. AFC 2004/007: 229
Granville, Evelyn B. AFC 2004/007: 045
Gravely, S. L. (Samuel Lee), 1922- AFC 2004/007: 046
Gray, Fred D., 1930- AFC 2004/007: 302
Green, Charles W., 1915-2004 AFC 2004/007: 047
Gregory, Dick AFC 2004/007: 048
Griggs, Ulysses S. AFC 2004/007: 270
Guillaume, Robert AFC 2004/007: 049
Gunter, Marcus, 1918-2003 AFC 2004/007: 165
Hampton, Grace, 1937- AFC 2004/007: 271
Hanna, Robert H. AFC 2004/007: 167
Hargraves, William, 1932- AFC 2004/007: 168
Harris, Barbara C. (Barbara Clementine) AFC 2004/007: 050
Harris, Charles Wesley, 1928- AFC 2004/007: 169
Hayes, Cleo AFC 2004/007: 291a AFC 2004/007: 293
Haysbert, Raymond, 1920-2010 AFC 2004/007: 170
Heath, Jimmy AFC 2004/007: 051
Height, Dorothy I. (Dorothy Irene), 1912-2010 AFC 2004/007: 052
Henry, Marion, 1927- AFC 2004/007: 171
Highsmith, Jessie Lee AFC 2004/007: 172
Hill, Oliver W., 1907-2007 AFC 2004/007: 053
Hilliard, Asa G. AFC 2004/007: 173
Holder, Geoffrey, 1930- AFC 2004/007: 054
Holloman, Charlotte, 1922- AFC 2004/007: 174
Hooks, Benjamin L. (Benjamin Lawson), 1925-2010 AFC 2004/007: 055
Houston, Cissy AFC 2004/007: 056
Hudgens, Jeanne, 1925- AFC 2004/007: 158
Hudson, Ola G., 1930- AFC 2004/007: 175
Hughes Wright, Roberta AFC 2004/007: 226
Irvis, K. Leroy, 1919-2006 AFC 2004/007: 057
Jackson, Esther Cooper AFC 2004/007: 177
Jackson, Genevieve E. AFC 2004/007: 229
Jackson, William R. AFC 2004/007: 176
Jeannette, Gertrude, 1914- AFC 2004/007: 272
Jenkins, Ella AFC 2004/007: 058
Johns, Harry J., 1921- AFC 2004/007: 178
Johnson, Colonel Stone, 1918- AFC 2004/007: 275
Johnson, John H. (John Harold), 1918-2005 AFC 2004/007: 059
Johnson, Katherine G. AFC 2004/007: 060
Johnson, Kenneth Lavon, 1937- AFC 2004/007: 274
Johnson, Mamie AFC 2004/007: 234
Johnson, Tobe AFC 2004/007: 179 AFC 2004/007: 273
Johnson-Brown, Hazel W. (Hazel Winifred), 1927- AFC 2004/007: 061
Jones, Clarence B. AFC 2004/007: 276
Jones, Howard O. AFC 2004/007: 180
Jones, Quincy, 1933- AFC 2004/007: 062
Jordan, Julia Gibson, 1924- AFC 2004/007: 181
Jupiter, Del Alexa Eagan, 1924- AFC 2004/007: 182
Kelly, Leontine T. C. (Leontine Turpeau Current) AFC 2004/007: 063
Kendrick, Dolores, 1927- AFC 2004/007: 183
Kennedy, Matthew, 1921- AFC 2004/007: 184
Key, Carrolena, 1932- AFC 2004/007: 277
Kimbrough, Charles E. AFC 2004/007: 185
King, B. B. AFC 2004/007: 064
King, Coretta Scott, 1927-2006 AFC 2004/007: 065
King, Mel AFC 2004/007: 186
Kitt, Eartha AFC 2004/007: 066
Kyles, Samuel Billy AFC 2004/007: 067
Layton, William W., 1915-2007 AFC 2004/007: 068
Ledbetter, Frankie AFC 2004/007: 187
Leffall, LaSalle D. AFC 2004/007: 069
Levy, John, 1912-2012 AFC 2004/007: 278
Lewis, Elma AFC 2004/007: 070
Llewellyn, J. Bruce, 1927-2010 AFC 2004/007: 071
Lloyd, Earl, 1928- AFC 2004/007: 072
Logan, Thomas W. S., 1912- AFC 2004/007: 189
Long, Jerome H., 1931- AFC 2004/007: 279
Lott, Thaddeus AFC 2004/007: 190
Lowery, Joseph E. AFC 2004/007: 073
Lucas, Leo, 1912- AFC 2004/007: 191
Mann, Barbara, 1931- AFC 2004/007: 192
Mann, John E., 1926- AFC 2004/007: 280
Marsalis, Ellis AFC 2004/007: 281
Martin, Edward W., 1929- AFC 2004/007: 193
Mayo, Gladys Elizabeth AFC 2004/007: 194
Mays, Nebraska, 1930- AFC 2004/007: 303
McCall, H. Carl AFC 2004/007: 305
McClure, Susie, 1915- AFC 2004/007: 282
McCord, Clinton, 1925- AFC 2004/007: 147
McEwan, Mary, 1919- AFC 2004/007: 195
McIntyre, Dorothy Layne, 1917- AFC 2004/007: 283
McKissack, Leatrice AFC 2004/007: 074
McKissick, Sara, 1920- AFC 2004/007: 196
McMullen, Stanley AFC 2004/007: 197
McQueen, Adele B. AFC 2004/007: 075
McRae, Bennie J., 1932- AFC 2004/007: 198
Meredith, James, 1933- AFC 2004/007: 076
Miller, Norma, 1919- AFC 2004/007: 077
Mingo, Lucy, 1931- AFC 2004/007: 268 AFC 2004/007: 266
Mitchell, Arthur, 1934- AFC 2004/007: 078
Mitchell, Ella Pearson AFC 2004/007: 079
Mitchell, Henry H., 1919- AFC 2004/007: 200 AFC 2004/007: 079
Mitchell, Parren J. AFC 2004/007: 080
Mitchell, Samuel, Jr. AFC 2004/007: 199
Moody, James, 1925-2010 AFC 2004/007: 081
Moore, Dan, 1935- AFC 2004/007: 284
Moore, LaVerne Jackson, 1917- AFC 2004/007: 201
Morrison, Toni AFC 2004/007: 082
Moses, Robert Parris AFC 2004/007: 083
Motley, Constance Baker, 1921-2005 AFC 2004/007: 084
Murphy, Camay Calloway AFC 2004/007: 285
Murphy, John H., 1916- AFC 2004/007: 286
Murray, Cecil AFC 2004/007: 287
Myers, Samuel L. (Samuel Lloyd), 1919- AFC 2004/007: 202
Nicholas, Fayard AFC 2004/007: 085
Noble, Gil AFC 2004/007: 086
Odetta, 1930-2008 AFC 2004/007: 088
Oldwine, Barbara H., 1923- AFC 2004/007: 203
O'Leary, Hazel Rollins, 1937- AFC 2004/007: 288
O'Neil, Buck, 1911-2006 AFC 2004/007: 087
Palmer, Anyim AFC 2004/007: 204
Parks, Gordon, 1912-2006 AFC 2004/007: 089
Payne, Essie Kathryn Scott AFC 2004/007: 205
Peters, Margaret, 1936- AFC 2004/007: 206
Petersen, Frank E. AFC 2004/007: 090
Pettway, China AFC 2004/007: 266
Pettway, Essie AFC 2004/007: 266
Poitier, Sidney AFC 2004/007: 091
Poussaint, Alvin F. AFC 2004/007: 092
Pratt, Frances E. AFC 2004/007: 207
Procope, Ernesta G., 1931- AFC 2004/007: 093
Proctor, Bernard S., 1921- AFC 2004/007: 208
Rangel, Charles B. AFC 2004/007: 094
Rates, Norman, 1924- AFC 2004/007: 209
Reese, Della AFC 2004/007: 095
Richards, Lloyd, 1919-2006 AFC 2004/007: 096
Ringgold, Faith AFC 2004/007: 097
Rivers, Robert, Jr. AFC 2004/007: 210
Robinson, Amelia Boynton, 1911- AFC 2004/007: 098
Robinson, Dolores AFC 2004/007: 232
Robinson, Rachel, 1922- AFC 2004/007: 099
Roundtree, Dovey Johnson, 1914- AFC 2004/007: 100
Russell, Bill, 1934- AFC 2004/007: 101
Russell, George L., 1929- AFC 2004/007: 289
Saar, Betye AFC 2004/007: 102
Saddler, Willieboyd, 1926- AFC 2004/007: 211
Sanchez, Sonia, 1934- AFC 2004/007: 103
Scott, Blanche, 1926- AFC 2004/007: 212
Scott, Frederick I., 1927- AFC 2004/007: 290
Shuttlesworth, Fred L., 1922-2011 AFC 2004/007: 104
Sizemore, Barbara A. AFC 2004/007: 105
Sklarek, Norma, 1928- AFC 2004/007: 106
Slaughter, John Brooks, 1934- AFC 2004/007: 296
Smith, Jessie Carney, 1930- AFC 2004/007: 213
Snyder, Charles AFC 2004/007: 214
Sternick, Barbara Peek, 1930- AFC 2004/007: 215
Stokes, Louis, 1925- AFC 2004/007: 297
Sumlin, Bernice, 1926- AFC 2004/007: 298
Sutton, Percy E. AFC 2004/007: 107
Taylor, Billy, 1921-2010 AFC 2004/007: 108
Taylor, Gardner C. AFC 2004/007: 109
Temple, Edward Stanley, 1927- AFC 2004/007: 216
Terry, Clark AFC 2004/007: 110
Tillman, Delores, 1929- AFC 2004/007: 217
Toussaint, Allen AFC 2004/007: 299
Tucker, C. DeLores AFC 2004/007: 111
Van Peebles, Melvin, 1932- AFC 2004/007: 300
Vivian, C. T. AFC 2004/007: 112
Von Blasingame, Billye, 1925- AFC 2004/007: 218
Waddell, William H., 1908-2007 AFC 2004/007: 113
Walker, Frances, 1924- AFC 2004/007: 219
Walker, Wyatt Tee AFC 2004/007: 114
Ward, James Harold, 1925- AFC 2004/007: 115
Washington, Walter E., 1915-2003 AFC 2004/007: 116
Welsing, Frances Cress, 1935- AFC 2004/007: 149
Wharton, Clifton R., 1926- AFC 2004/007: 117
Wharton, Dolores D. AFC 2004/007: 117
Wilder, Lawrence Douglas, 1931- AFC 2004/007: 118
Wilkins, Roger W., 1932- AFC 2004/007: 240
Wilkinson, DeLois, 1924-2005 AFC 2004/007: 220
Williams, Floyd N. AFC 2004/007: 225
Williams, Frances, 1934- AFC 2004/007: 221
Williams, Grant, 1920- AFC 2004/007: 222
Williams, Jamye Coleman, 1918- AFC 2004/007: 223
Williams, McDonald, 1917- AFC 2004/007: 223
Williams, Ruth, 1905- AFC 2004/007: 224
Willie, Charles Vert, 1927- AFC 2004/007: 119
Wilson, Nancy, 1937- AFC 2004/007: 301
Woodruff, John, 1915-2007 AFC 2004/007: 120
Yette, Samuel F. AFC 2004/007: 121
Young, Andrew, 1932- AFC 2004/007: 122
Young, Nettie, 1917- AFC 2004/007: 266 AFC 2004/007: 267
Zeigler, Harvey, 1920- AFC 2004/007: 228